<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-04-17T00:42:07+00:00</updated><id>https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Mohammad-Javad Darvishi Bayazi website </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Time Series Forecasting demo</title><link href="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/ts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time Series Forecasting demo"/><published>2024-09-27T18:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-27T18:37:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/ts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/ts/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="demo-of-deep-learning-models-for-time-series-forecasting">Demo of Deep Learning Models for Time Series Forecasting</h1> <p>Time series forecasting is a technique used to predict future values based on previously observed values over time. If you have data collected over time, such as sales figures, temperatures, or stock prices, you can analyze historical patterns to make informed predictions about future trends. This can be incredibly useful in various fields, including finance, economics, and operations.</p> <h2 id="try-our-interactive-demo">Try Our Interactive Demo</h2> <p>We invite you to explore our demo, where you can paste your own time series data and see the forecast generated by advanced deep learning models. Here’s how it works:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Input Your Data</strong>: Simply copy and paste your time series data into the provided text box. The data should be in a simple format, separated by commas.</p> <p>For example:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>112, 118, 132, 129, 121, 135, 148, 148, 136, 119
</code></pre></div> </div> </li> <li> <p><strong>Adjust the Forecast Horizon</strong>: Use the slider to select the forecast horizon in months. This allows you to specify how far into the future you want the predictions to extend.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Automatic Forecasting</strong>: Once you’ve pasted your data and adjusted the forecast horizon, the system will automatically generate forecasts for you, providing visualizations to help you understand the predictions.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Visualize the Results</strong>: The demo will plot both your historical data and the forecast, complete with confidence intervals, so you can see the predicted values in context.</p> </li> </ol> <iframe src="https://mj-bfm.hf.space" frameborder="0" width="850" height="850"></iframe> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>With this simple yet powerful demo, you can easily see how deep learning models can be applied to time series forecasting. It’s a great way to explore the potential of advanced machine learning techniques in analyzing and predicting future trends from historical data.</p> <p>Feel free to experiment with your data and see how accurate the forecasts can be!</p> <p>For comments, feedback, or any questions, please reach out to me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mjdarvishi/">LinkedIn</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="demo-posts"/><category term="forecasting,"/><category term="time-series,"/><category term="demo"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A demo of time series forecasting]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Psycho-LLaVA: Psychology of Large Language and Vision Assistant</title><link href="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/psycho-llava-psychology-of-large-language-and-vision-assistant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Psycho-LLaVA: Psychology of Large Language and Vision Assistant"/><published>2024-04-08T22:11:22+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-08T22:11:22+00:00</updated><id>https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/psycho-llava-psychology-of-large-language-and-vision-assistant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mohammadjavadd.github.io/home/blog/2024/psycho-llava-psychology-of-large-language-and-vision-assistant/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>